today I'm going to be sharing with you
what I consider to be the best swing
trading strategy that I've ever created
or discovered this is a strategy I've
used now consistently for over six years
and it's proven to be the most effective
swing trading strategy I have ever used
so in this video I'll be explaining this
entire strategy to you and also be
showing you some of the currency pairs
that I'm looking to trade this strategy
with throughout the next couple of weeks
so if that sounds good go ahead and
click that like button for me go ahead
and subscribe if you are new and I'll
catch you after the intro and disclaimer
[Music]
in just a second we're gonna be diving
into the full strategy tutorial but
before we do that there's actually three
things that no matter what strategy you
learn your trading will never be
successful or profitable consistently if
you don't master and use these three
things so we're going to talk about
those a little bit first number one is
discipline if you cannot stay
disciplined to a consistently profitable
trading strategy then you're going to be
switching strategies moving your stop up
and down moving your target up and down
you're going to make a ton of trading
mistakes and that's going to cause you
to slowly lose money in your account so
if you can't master your discipline it
doesn't matter what trading strategy you
actually learn you will still fail as a
Trader trust me I learned this the hard
way after over a year of struggling to
create profits not because I didn't have
a profitable strategy but because I
didn't Master my discipline so keep that
in mind as we move forward number two is
your risk management how much can you
control the greed you have to try to get
rich as fast as possible the more we
risk on a trade the more we can make but
obviously the more we risk on a trade
the more we stand to lose on that trade
as well and at the very beginning of
your trading career before you're even
good at trading the problem I see most
Traders have is they're risking five ten
percent of their account just trying to
get rich as fast as possible and that is
a great way
to blow your account not a great way to
get rich you will 99 of people that do
that will blow their account and a good
risk management plan will also help you
with number one which is discipline and
your trading mindset so keep that in
mind as well it's important to have a
good risk management plan again another
lesson that I learned the hard way that
full year I spent losing money trying to
learn how to trade I was risking way too
much of my account and unable to control
my emotions enough to stick to one
strategy unable to control my emotions
in general and I was an absolute wreck
throughout that entire year because I
was risking too much on every trade I
placed and number three is having the
proper expectations again coming into
trading at the very beginning of my
career I was Roofing houses and looking
for a way out looking for a way to make
enough money to at least quit Roofing
houses and honestly I thought I would be
able to get rich within a year and those
expectations led to a lot of mistakes so
correcting your expectations to a more
reasonable level can also help with your
mind mindset can help with your
discipline and so number three is have
proper expectations around trading be
prepared to spend a long time learning
how to trade it's difficult be prepared
to use good risk management where you're
not going to get rich super fast but you
can acquire wealth over time if that's
not something you're prepared for
trading may not be for you you may be
better off trying to start a different
business now before we jump into the
strategy itself I want you to notice
something trading a strategy is the
physical form of pressing the buy and
sell button where you can actually make
money right
well the three things that I just listed
had nothing to do with physically
pressing the button a large majority of
your trading success is going to come
down not to the strategy that you're
trading but to the six inches between
your ears it's going to come down to
your trading mindset your ability to
handle fear and greed your discipline
and your ability to use good risk
management and have proper expectations
so keep all that in mind as we move
forward but now let's take a look at a
full tutorial of what I consider the
best swing trading strategy that I
currently have in my trading Arsenal
first off I'm going to be explaining the
eight steps that go along with this
strategy to you as a brief overview of
the strategy itself then we'll dive into
each of them in detail first thing that
we do with this trading strategy is we
look for a major structure level on the
daily chart this strategy although we're
trading it on the four hour chart
utilizes two different Dom frames it
utilizes the daily chart for major
levels of structure and then the four
hour chart for confirmation and entry so
step number one which I'll explain in
just a moment because we have a very
specific way here at TTC that we
identify these major structure levels
that keeps this trading strategy as
objective and easy to follow as possible
so I'll explain those in just a second
the next thing we look for step two of
the strategy is a four hour confirmation
which you'll also learn in just a moment
step three is the actual entry reason
why are we pressing the buy or sell
button step number four is an objective
rule I use for a stop loss where am I
getting out of the market when I know my
analysis was not correct I need an
objective rule for that in every
strategy I trade this one's no different
step number five is an objective rule
for when I get out when I'm right this
is my Target price if everything goes
correct compared to my analysis what I
thought was going to happen happens I
need an objective way that I'm getting
out when I'm right so I can actually
take some profit step number six is
always use proper risk management step
number seven is going to be to place the
actual trade for me and step number
eight is to stay disciplined so there
was an overview of the strategy let's
now take a look at the specific way a I
spot major structure levels on the daily
chart while utilizing this trading
strategy so personally I use this
trading strategy for Trend continuation
as well as counter Trend trading you
don't have to do that if you would
rather just be a trained continuation
Trader that's completely fine but right
now let me explain the two ways I find
Trend continuation levels utilizing this
strategy so in a trending Market we'll
go down to a chart and take a look at
this to make it easier but I want to
explain it on whiteboard first in a
trending Market we normally have a
situation where price is making higher
highs and higher lows in this trending
Market I am only paying attention to two
levels nothing else don't over
complicate your trading strategy I'm
only paying attention to two areas based
on where price is so if price is
trending up and it's right here and we
start to see a pullback the only two
levels for Trend continuation trades
that I am paying attention to are going
to be the previous level of resistance
that was broken
and the previous level of support right
down here these are the only two levels
I'm looking to trade keep that in mind
and an added rule for this becoming a
major structure level that I'm actually
looking in for possible trades is that
this level must have been tested
multiple times I must see at least two
tests of one of these levels so looking
back left it would look something like
this for this previous resistance level
to be a major structure level I'm
looking to trade around I would need it
to be tested multiple times not only be
the latest resistance broken but also be
a level that's tested multiple times not
only for this to be our previous swing
low before Trend continuation but also
this level to be tested multiple times
so if I was only trading Trend
continuation this would be how I spot
the major levels of structure on the
daily chart let me do a bearish example
of this it's literally the same thing
just flipped upside down down we would
have prices pushing lower pushing lower
and we would need to see prices start to
pull back and at that point we'd be
looking at the previous level of support
that was broken
and the previous level of resistance or
previous swing high before the
continuation of this downtrend so would
I be looking anywhere else for a
possible trade using the strategy the
answer is no these are the only two
levels I'm paying attention to and what
are the other rules I need this level if
I'm going to be trading from it to have
been tested more than once tested here
would actually count as one tested here
would count as two I need this level of
previous support that could become
resistance to have been tested more than
once so we would have this desk as our
first test we'd have this as our second
one and that would give me valid major
levels of structure if I was looking at
the daily chart planning to trade Trend
continuation with this strategy these
two levels is where I would be looking
for possible trades on the four hour
chart so if Trend continuation is all I
was trading with this strategy these
would be the levels I would be looking
for on a daily chart now what I want to
do is is explained the counter Trend
levels I look for because again I trade
this strategy Trend continuation and for
counter Trend traits so let me explain
that now in a trending Market we
eventually always get a reversal after
this reversal happens in order to trade
counter Trend in this new downtrending
environment what I'm doing is I'm
looking at our swing low before the
start of a pullback this level is not
going to be a level of support for me
because in a downtrend we are very
likely to do what to break below that
level so what I'm going to be doing for
a counter Trend trade is I'm going to be
looking not at this level but I'll put a
horizontal line at this level go below
it and look left to the very next level
price will hit in this case it's this
level of support right here so this
level would be my counter Trend level
for this trading strategy and what else
do I need just like with train
continuation I'll need this level to be
a level that has been tested multiple
times so if we're pushing lower and then
we begin to continue pushing lower this
is where I would look for possible buy
trades in a counter Trend trading
environment I would look for the next
level price is going to hit up support
then I would make sure that that level
has been tested multiple times then I
would look for possible trades in that
area on the four hour chart this is the
only way I'm looking for possible
counter Trend levels the very next level
price will hit that has been tested
multiple times let me do a bearish
example of this as well so after a
bearish trend
we will almost always eventually see
what see a reversal while this reversal
is happening I'm going to take a look at
price and at my most recent swing High
I'm going to put a horizontal line there
and am I going to use this level
as a level of resistance
well I'm in an uptrend so this level
before the pullback started it's very
likely to break if this uptrend
continues so why would I look there for
possible resistance why would I look
there for a shorting opportunity to go
short if this level is likely to break I
wouldn't I would put a horizontal line
here I would look above the resistance
level the swing I before the start of
the pullback I would go above that look
left and find the next level of
resistance price will inevitably hit if
it continues higher this will be my
level of resistance I look at as a major
structure level on a daily time frame
for possible trades the other
qualification that must be met is that
this level must have been tested not
just once but at least two times it must
have been a level tested multiple times
and this is how I would look for counter
Trend bearish levels of structure on my
daily chart before dropping down to the
four hour and looking for possible
entries so this is the extremely
specific way we look for major structure
levels here at TTC and this is how I
find the most optimal trading zones for
this specific strategy alright so now
let's take a look at a couple of
examples of this entire strategy on some
real charts so that I not only can show
you what it looks like on real charts
but also explain the entries and stops
and targets I use for this strategy so
we're on the Euro Aussie daily chart
I'll go ahead and let you know this is
actually a counter Trend trade but what
do we see that's happened so far on this
chart would you consider this a reversal
I would and the reason is Price is Right
Here obviously and what we've seen is
price go from making higher lows and
higher highs on a consistent basis to
now making a lower high and a lower low
would that be the case we have a
reversal so if we were trading Trend
continuation do you see a level that
would qualify as a major structure level
here on the daily chart
hopefully you pointed out this level the
reason is this is an area that is the
most recent support broken by price and
along with that it's been tested
multiple times now as I said this is a
counter Trend trade so that was just
kind of review for our train
continuation areas what about a counter
Trend area so price is pushing lower our
first step is to find the swing low and
I'm going to put a horizontal line on
that swing low so that when I look left
I can tell the lowest point price has
gotten to this level is not going to be
a support level because in a downtrend
it's likely to break but if we look
below this level and look left we can
see that there's a prominent level of
support right here what's the next thing
we need to do well we'll put a
horizontal line there and we'll check to
see if this level has been tested
multiple times what do you see looking
left this level has in fact been tested
multiple times so the next step for me
is to create a Zone here that makes
sense I don't have exact rules for this
Zone but this is something like that
zone would look so this would be our
Zone the major structure level Zone and
the optimal Trading Zone that I'm
looking for possible trades in on the
four hour chart so the next step is to
see when price actually makes it all the
way into our Zone which is right here
and at this point this is when I would
drop down to a smaller time frame the
four hour chart for this exact strategy
so on the four hour chart our rules were
that I'm looking for a confirmation and
for this strategy and for the scope of
this video the confirmation is going to
be double bottoms and double tops so
what we're waiting on on the four hour
chart is a double bottom and this by
trade here on the four hour chart let's
take a look and see what price does
price pushes around eventually pushing
up pushing down pushing back up back
down and there we go we have price
creating at this point a double bottom
and we almost actually have a triple
bottom in this situation I'm gonna count
it as a double bottom though as you can
see price pushed lower creating our
first bottom the neckline of the double
bottom and the second Bottom now the
rules for a double bottom for me are
very simple I'm looking for price to
create our first bottom which we will
count right here
pushing lower at this first bottom as
soon as I see candles start pushing up
from that first Bottom of My Double
bottom I grab a box tool and I create a
box between the lowest body and the
lowest Wick of that candle so this gray
ish box is what I call my termination
Zone and again it goes from the body
of the lowest low of the double bottom
down to the wick of that lowest low of
the double bottom what I need is candles
to at least touch this area candles can
go below it with a wick what I cannot
see is a candle close below this area as
long as those criteria are met I have a
valid double bottom so that is our four
hour confirmation and as I said we're
also looking at four hour four hour
actual entry reason so we're looking
here for an entry reason or entry reason
after the confirmation of a double
bottom for me is going to be some type
of Candlestick pattern for this case I
actually use this engulfing bar that
followed a long whip candle to the
downside and this is a trade that I not
only placed but also sent out to all the
members of the TTC Forex University I'll
put a screenshot of the email I sent
them to the right hand side of the
screen if you're interested in learning
more about the TTC 4X University all you
got to do is click the top Link in the
description we'll go ahead and put a
position tool on here though this is is
exactly where I enter these trades after
entering the trades here at this Zone I
normally do one times the ATR indicator
below the lowest Wick of the double
bottom the ATR indicator is right up
here you can find it by typing in ATR to
essentially any trading platform and you
can see at the moment it's about 44 Pips
so what I'm going to do is go 44 Pips
below the lowest low of this double
bottom that would put me at roughly 107
Pips for the stop loss and I normally
manage the position but if you are a
brand new Trader that might be quite
complicated or if you have some type of
full-time job or another obligation you
may not be able to manage your positions
so when I'm unable to do that I actually
go with a fixed Target of a 1.4 to 1
reward to risk ratio on these types of
Trades when they're counter Trend so
with that being the case to break this
trade down yet again we saw our major
structure level on the daily chart it
was a counter Trend level we then waited
for price to get into that zone that we
pointed out on the daily we waited for
confirmation the confirmation is what
it's going to be that double bottom we
then waited on an exact reason for entry
and what would that be some type of
Candlestick pattern my favorites are
either to use a hammer candle or some
type of engulfing or close above bar
something that's showing that we have
bullish momentum after the double bottom
that's when I actually press the buy
button my actual entry is after the
Candlestick pattern the stop loss is one
times the ATR indicator below the double
bottom and if I'm using fixed targets I
normally use a 1.4 to 1 reward to risk
ratio and now let's check out how this
trade played out
we pushed down a bit and did consolidate
getting a little bit close to our stop
loss but not near enough to actually
stop us out and then eventually price
did in fact head up and go in our favor
here on the Canada Swiss we have a train
continuation opportunity that I want you
to help me out with so what has happened
so far so far price has done what we've
come from a swing High pushed down to a
swing low pushed up Consolidated a bit
in this pullback and then eventually
broke below our previous level of
resistance so with this being the case
where are we going to put a horizontal
line to try to find our major structure
level out here on the daily chart we're
going to do so right at the previous
level of support that was broken our
next criteria is that this level must
have been tested multiple times we're on
the daily chart looking at the level
we're going to scroll backwards and see
do we get another test right here
another major area of support where the
cad Swiss used this area as a major
level of structure so what we're going
to do now is create a little zone of
major structure here for Possible
Trading opportunities I'll color this
one red so we can tell that it's a
resistance level and the next step is to
wait for price to push back up into our
zone so that's exactly what we would be
doing here now what's happened well now
price has gotten into our Zone The Next
Step once that happens is that I'm going
to be dropping down to the four hour
chart to look for confirmation if
confirmation on a bullish trade was a
double bottom what do you think
confirmation here is going to be on our
four hour chart confirmation is going to
look like a double top so at this point
we're waiting for a double top here on
the four hour chart let's see what we
get as we get price pushing around we go
a little bit above our Zone this would
not be out of our Zone yet so we're
still considering this inside of our
major structure level now the rules for
a double top for me are going to be that
the highest top created before the start
of the pullback I'm going to now take a
box from the bodies to that highest
point and this is what I consider a
termination zone so I need price to at
least touch this area but price cannot
close above it price can close inside of
it that's not a big deal but again the
only thing I don't want to see is price
closing above this box because that
equals train continuation and that means
we're likely to head higher so with that
being the case let's see what happens
with the cad Swiss As I push forward and
a little more here what do we have are
all the rules met for us to actually
place an entry
well we have our major level of
structure on the daily chart pointed out
we have our confirmation on the four
hour chart being this double top what do
we need next some type of Candlestick
pattern like this big closed below red
candle showing selling pressure after a
double top so yes this would be where I
would go ahead and place my entry after
placing my entry what are my stops and
targets well my stop is going to be one
ATR which is 22 Pips so 22 Pips above
the highest point of the double top
which would be roughly a 42 pip stop
loss in this case and as I said for a
Target on fixed targets I like to look
for about a 1.4 to 1. now again this is
another trade that I placed in a lab
account and also sent out to all of our
members you can see that looking left
right here let's go ahead and hit play
to see if this trade worked out
so as you can see there we actually did
clip that 1.4 to 1 reward to risk ratio
Target the last trade we're going to
take a look at is a trade I'm in right
now as we speak utilizing exactly what
you've learned so far in this video to
prove that I actually traded this with
real money on a live account so with
this pound dollar daily chart what are
you seeing
hopefully you said you're seeing an
uptrend as prices are in fact making new
higher highs here was our previous low
what are the two levels I'm going to be
looking at for Trend continuation trades
well those two levels are right here at
the previous resistance that was broken
and also right here at the previous
level of support now we didn't get
anything from this previous level of
resistance but since that's the case I
started looking here for Possible
Trading opportunities because on the
daily chart this is not only our swing
low before the impulsive move up but
also has been what
has been tested multiple times I was
testing you there so it's been tested
multiple times it's a valid major
structure level so now I was just
waiting for price to get into my zone
and once price got into the Zone I
actually just exit out of Market replay
mode and go down to the four hour chart
to show you what I was seeing after
price got into our Zone it created what
I think is probably the ugliest double
bottom I've ever traded so right here
what we have is price push lower created
one bottom here pushed up to a neckline
after some consolidation pushed back
down and then we did in fact get a
Candlestick pattern so the confirmation
here is going to be this double bottom
right here after the confirmation what
am I looking for I'm looking for a
Candlestick pattern that shows buying
pressure that came with this big green
candle here with the long Wick to the
bottom side for me that counted as
buying pressure and that's when I
decided to go ahead and enter this trade
currently pretty much break even on the
straight I had no idea how it's going to
play out but hopefully we'll see the
pound dollar push up a bit and hit my
targets so that's the full strategy but
don't leave yet I'm gonna be showing you
my daily levels of structure my major
levels of structure own a daily chart
that I'm looking in for possible trades
throughout the next week or so and if
you're someone that's a complete
beginner we actually just created a
brand new and completely free beginners
course that you're welcome to sign up
for you'll get access to it immediately
and that's going to be linked in the
description or you can go to the link
that you see on the screen right now so
if you're brand new to trading you're
not ready to just go out and start
trading a strategy right now you need to
learn the basics learn a lot about risk
management learn a lot about trading
psychology and that beginner course will
actually help you to do now what I want
to do is take you through a few of the
currency Pairs and major levels of
structure I'm actually looking to trade
in right now using this exact strategy
you learned throughout this video so
first off we have the dollar Swiss here
on the daily chart and what I'm looking
at here is a downtrend move pushing
lower a new swing low followed by a new
lower high followed by another new lower
low at that point I'm looking back at
what the previous level of structure
support that was broken it also has been
tested multiple times looking left now
with that being the case what am I going
to do if price gets into the Zone if
price gets into the zone I'm dropping
down to my four hour chart and I'm going
to execute the strategy exactly how you
learned I'll look for confirmation with
a double top I'll look for a Candlestick
pattern over here at the end of the
double top and that'll be my entry stops
above Target somewhere around a 1.4 to
one reward to risk ratio again I manage
my position so when I hit this 1.4 I
don't just take my targets automatically
I actually move my stop to break even
and manage the position Edition as it
continues lower but you may not be able
to do that with a full-time job and also
something else I want to point out is
you could be as aggressive or
conservative with this strategy as you'd
like to be I just used one version of
confirmation in order to make this video
a little bit shorter but you could also
use things like a Candlestick pattern
with no double top confirmation in this
case you may lose more trades but you
also will get a lot more trading
opportunities so it may prove to be more
profitable or just as profitable and
you'll get a higher frequency of Trades
just something to think about and play
around with but in the scope of this
strategy we'll be waiting on this bear
the dollar Swiss to come up between the
area of
0.8907 and
0.8841 and give us some type of
confirmation followed by an entry reason
next up we have the Aussie Canada here
on the Aussie Canada we have a counter
Trend Zone price is pushing lower at the
moment if we scroll back left though we
have this area that sticks out like a
sore thumb this area pushed the market
around like a big kid on the playground
we look left it's also been tested
multiple times as well so with that
being the case I'm waiting here on the
daily chart for what to happen I'll be
waiting for price to come down into my
zone between 0.8 665 and 0.8609 if price
does get in that area I'll be dropping
down the four hour time frame looking
for my confirmation being a double
bottom and looking for a Candlestick
pattern for entry stops below the zone
or below the lowest low of the double
bottom followed by a Target wherever you
would like 1.4 to 1 is what I use for
fixed targets next up we have the pound
New Zealand here on the pound New
Zealand we have a pair that has in fact
broken above a previous level of
structure resistance so this was an
uptrend pushing up higher high
higher low higher high high or low we
have some consolidation in this pullback
before we get a breakout of this little
ascending wedge so would that be the
case this green area is going to be our
major level of structure and with that
being the case what I'm going to be
waiting on is price to pull back into
this level between
2.0950 and
2.082 and in this areas where I'll be
looking for confirmation and possible
entry reasons next up I'm looking at the
Euro New Zealand very similar here we
have price that has just pushed above an
ascending wedge that has made multiple
resistance levels since this area has
been tested so many times I counted as
an otz optimal Trading Zone otherwise
known as a major structure level and
with that being the case I'm going to be
waiting for price to pull back to that
level in this area between
1.8081 and
1.7971 I'll be looking for possible
confirmation and entries in this Zone
next up we have the Euro Aussie here on
the Euro Aussie we have price that is
just broken above a major level of
structure that's been tested multiple
times with this being the case I'll be
waiting for a pullback to this area and
if you can't see the one two three move
here let me back up here's our one two
three move for a trending move this
being the latest and most recent level
of structure resistance broken then
looking left and seeing that it has been
tested multiple times is what gave us a
valid major structure level a valid otz
here in this area so if we get that
pullback down to 1.6607 between that and
the 1.6487 level I'll be looking for
confirmation and entry in that zone and
our last pair is gonna be the Euro Swiss
here on the Euro Swiss we've moved away
from the Zone since I pointed it out at
the beginning of the week but this is
very similar to the dollar Swiss we have
price pushing lower creating a lower
high after a lower low and then another
lower low with that being the case we're
looking at that previous level of
support seeing if it's been tested
multiple times which it has so if we get
a push up in this pullback all the way
to the area between
0.9719 and 0.9684 this will be the area
I look for possible confirmation and
entry from on the Euro Swiss now as I
said earlier we just released a
completely free beginner Forex course
that'll teach you everything you need to
know about the basics of trading how to
become profitable it's going to teach
you about all types of orders spreads
margin trading the platform I use
technical analysis go check it out it's
completely free you'll learn about
trading psychology you'll learn some of
the strategies I use how to back test
and again you'll learn about risk
management and essentially you'll learn
the process of building a full trading
plan and again it's completely free you
can go to the link on the screen or you
can go to the description and click the
link beside the beginner Forex course
now if you're ready for some more
advanced training we also have some
space available in the TTC 4X University
which includes our entire University
style course which is going to teach you
everything from the basics to the exact
strategies I use on a daily basis the
risk management and trading psychology
tips and tricks that I've learned over
the past decade of my own trading career
my full discretionary trading strategy
along with much much more including
priority email support where I'll answer
any of the questions that you have the
email analysis you saw earlier in the
videos also included in this so feel
free to check that out it's gonna be the
top Link in the description or go to
www.ttcfxuniversity.com that's going to
do it for today's video go ahead and hit
that like button go and subscribe
comment if you made it to the end and
pray with me that the pound dollar
continues higher so I can actually make
some money on this trade I'll see you
guys in the next one talk soon